Finding Aid for the Delmore Schwartz Papers LSC.1005
UCLA Library Special Collections
Delmore Schwartz papers
1923-1966
UCLA Library Special Collections
Schwartz, Delmore
LSC.1005
35.0 linear feet (70 boxes)
Delmore David Schwartz (1913-1966) was an English professor, editor (1943-47) and associate editor (1947-55) of the Partisan Review, and the poetry editor of the New republic (1955-57). He also wrote poetry, plays, essays, translations, and stories, including In dreams begin responsibilities (1938), The world is a wedding (1948), and Summer knowledge: new and selected poems, 1938-1958 (1959), which won the Bollingen Prize in poetry and the Shelley Memorial Award in 1960. The collection consists of books and journals from Schwartz's library, most of which are heavily-annotated with his notes, nine holographic notebooks, and correspondence.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Phoenix Book Shop, purchase, 1967 & 1968.
Zeitlin & Verbrugge, purchase, 1970.
Gift of Kenneth A. Schwartz, 1981.
Gift of David Holzman, 1983.
Black Sun Books, purchase, 1984.
Gift of J. Howard Woolmer, 1988.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942337473606533
Biography
Delmore David Schwartz was born on December 8, 1913 in Brooklyn, New York; attended University of Wisconsin, 1931; BA in philosophy, New York University, 1935; attended Harvard University, 1935-37; Briggs-Copeland Instructor in English Composition, 1940 and assistant Professor of English composition, 1946-47, Harvard University; editor (1943-47) and associate editor (1947-55), Partisan Review; poetry editor, New republic, 1955-57; visiting lecturer at New York University, Kenyon School of English, Indiana School of Letters, Princeton University, University of Chicago; visiting professor, Syracuse University; literary consultant to New directions; wrote poetry, plays, essays, translations, and stories, including In dreams begin responsibilities (1938), The world is a wedding (1948), and Summer knowledge: new and selected poems, 1938-1958 (1959), which won the Bollingen Prize in poetry and Shelley Memorial Award in 1960; he died on July 11, 1966 in New York City.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of books and journals from the library of Delmore Schwartz, most of which are heavily-annotated with his notes, and nine holographic notebooks and a few original letters of Schwartz. Includes mostly paperback editions of fiction, literary criticism and art history, as well as 12 volumes of Partisan Review, 1942-54.
Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Poets, American -- New York (State) -- New York.; Schwartz, Delmore -- Archives
- Books from the library of Delmore Schwartz
  - Oxford anthology of American literature, chosen and edited by William Rose Benet and Norman Holmes Pearson. New York: Oxford University Press, 1938, Call number: PS507.O98 1938 (Box 3)
  - Dead Sea Scrolls in English [translated by Gèza Vermés]. Baltimore: Penguin, 1962, Call number: BM487.A3 V4 (Box 9)
  - Ring of words: an anthology of song texts the original texts selected and translated with an introduction by Philip L. Miller. Garden City, N.Y.: Anchor Books, 1966, Call number: ML54.6.R56 1966 (Box 9)
  - Great French short stories edited with introductions by Germaine Bree. New York: Dell Pub. Co., 1960, Call number: PQ1278.G74 (Box 19)
    General note
    Additions, June 1981
  - New world writing: fourth Mentor selection. New York: New American Library, 1953, Call number: PN6014.N457 1953 (Box 19)
  - Psalms, a prayer book: also, the canticles of the Roman breviary: new English translation, with ecclesiastical approbation, including the new Latin version from the Hebrew by the professors of the Pontifical Biblical Institute, authorized by Pope Pius X New York; Boston: Benziger Bros., 1947, Call number: BS1422 1947a (Box 20)
  - Anchor book of stories selected and with an introduction by Randall Jarrell. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1958, Call number: PN6014.A53 1958 (Box 23)
  - Partisan Review anthology edited by William Phillips and Philip Rahv. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1962, Call number: PN6014.F621 1962 (Box 26)
  - Pocket Bible: the Old and New Testaments in the King James version an abridgment with preface by Cyril C. Richardson of The Bible designed to be read as living literature, as edited and arranged by Ernest Sutherland Bates. New York: Washington Square Press, 1961, Call number: BS391.R53 1961 (Box 30)
  - Voices of Dissent: a collection of articles from Dissent magazine. New York: Grove Press, 1958, Call number: AC5.D632v (Box 30)
  - Penguin book of Latin verse introduced and edited by Frederick Brittain. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1962, Call number: PA6121.A7 B7 (Box 31)
  - Penguin book of Latin verse: with plain prose translations of each poem introduced and edited by Frederick Brittain. Baltimore, Md.: Penguin Books, 1962, Call number: PA6121.A7 B7 (Box 31)
  - Bildwerke des Naumburger Doms: 44 bildtafeln mit einem Geleitwort von Wilhelm Pinder. Leipzig: Insel-Verlag, 1959, Call number: NA5586.N3 B55 1959 (Box 44)
  - Partisan reader: ten years of Partisan review, 1934-1944: an anthology edited by William Phillips and Philip Rahv; introduction by Lionel Trilling. New York: The Dial press, 1946, Call number: PN6014.P25 1946 (Box 53)
  - Holy bible: containing the Old and New Testaments translated out of the original tongues and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, set forth in 1611 and commonly known as the King James version. New York: American Bible Society, 1952, Call number: BS148 1952.N48 (Box 57)
  - Holy Bible: containing the Old and New Testaments translated out of the original tongues and with the former translations diligently compared, commonly known as the Authorized (King James) version. Chicago: Gideons International, 1958, Call number: BS185 1958.C53 (Box 57)
  - Norton anthology of English literature. New York: W. W. Norton, 1962, Call number: PR1109.A22 1962 (Box 51)
  - Mont-Saint-Michel and Chartres With an introduction by Ernest Samuels. [New York]: New American Library, 1961, Call number: DC20.A2 1961 (Box 12)
  - Stendhal: notes on a novelist. New York: Noonday Press, 1959, Call number: PQ2441.A216s (Box 25)
  - Fables in slang, and More fables in slang illustrated by Clyde J. Newman; with an introduction by E. F. Bleiler. New York: Dover Publications, 1960, Call number: PS1006.A6f 1960 (Box 12)
  - House is not a home. New York: Popular Library, 1953, Call number: HQ146.N7 A4 1953x (Box 12)
  - Let us now praise famous men; three tenant families. New York: Ballantine Books, 1966, Call number: F326.A17 1966x (Box 1)
  - Thunder over South Parish. New York: Dell Pub. Co., 1964, Call number: PS3501.L4829 N49 1964 (Box 26)
  - Kind of anger. New York: Bantam, 1965, Call number: PR6001.M48 K56 1965 (Box 40)
  - Private devotions of Lancelot Andrewes: Preces privatae translated, with an introduction and notes by F. E. Brightman, and including"Lancelot Andrewes" (1926) by T. S. Eliot. New York: Meridian Books, 1961, Call number: BV4830.A652 1961 (Box 12)
  - Hollywood Babylon. [Phoenix, Ariz.: Associated Professional Services], 1965, Call number: PN1993.5.U65 A58E (Box 30)
  - Pope John XXIII with an additional chapter by Glenn D. Kittler. New York: Dell, 1961, Call number: BX1378.2.A7 (Box 18)
  - Golden hammer. Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett, 1964, Call number: PS3551.R345 G65 1964 (Box 27)
  - Woman of straw. New York: Bantam Books, 1964, Call number: PQ2661.R58 F413 1964 (Box 26)
  - Art of the High Gothic era with the collaboration of J.A. Schmoll gen. Eisenwerth and contributions by Hans H. Hofstatter. [Translated by Peter Gorge]. New York: Crown Publishers, 1965, Call number: N6310.A833 (Box 17)
  - Aubrey's brief lives edited from the original manuscripts and with a life of John Aubrey by Oliver Lawson Dick; foreword by Edmund Wilson. Ann Arbor: University of Michigan Press, 1962, Call number: DA447.A3 A8 1962 (Box 33)
  - Introduction to Romance languages and literature: Latin, French, Spanish, Provencal, Italian translated from the French by Guy Daniels. New York: Capricorn Books, 1961, Call number: PC41.A91iE (Box 27)
  - Confessions of Saint Augustine translated by E. B. Pusey. New York: Collier Books, 1961, Call number: BR65.A92 A3 1961 (Box 44)
  - Emma with an afterword by Graham Hough. New York: New American Library, 1964, Call number: PR4034.E53 1964 (Box 1)
  - Pride and prejudice with an afterword by Joann Morse. New York: New American Library, 1961, Call number: PR4030.P93 1961 (Box 13)
  - Green mare translated from the French by Norman Denny. New York: Atheneum, 1963, Call number: PQ2601.Y54 J813 1963 (Box 22)
  - Super-Americans: a picture of life in the United States, as brought into focus, bigger than life, in the land of the millionaires--Texas. New York: New American Library, 1963, Call number: F391.2.B3 1963 (Box 25)
  - Age of the junkman. Greenwich, CT: Fawcett Publications, 1963, Call number: PS3552.A4653 A33 1963 (Box 25)
  - Three for the money. New York: Pocket Books, 1963, Call number: PS3503.A5575 T47 (Box 26)
  - Girl with the golden eyes. New York: Paperback Library, 1962, Call number: PQ2167.F5 E5 1962 (Box 38)
  - Nightwood introduction by T.S. Eliot. New York: New Directions, 1961, Call number: PS3503.B26n 1961 (Box 12)
  - Antiphon: a play. New York: Farrar, Straus & Cudahy, 1958, Call number: PS3503.B26a 1958 (Box 18)
  - Nightwood introduction by T.S. Eliot. New York: J. Laughlin, 1937, Call number: PS3503.A614 N53 1937 (Box 54)
  - Eight great comedies. [New York]: New American Library, 1958, Call number: PN6112.B264e (Box 13)
  - Universe and Dr. Einstein with a foreword by Albert Einstein. New York: New American Library, 1957, Call number: QC6.B33 1957 (Box 53)
  - Modern European poetry: French, German, Greek, Italian, Russian, Spanish. New York: Bantam Books, 1966, Call number: PN6101.B3 1966 (Box 1)
  - Romans. Baltimore, Md.: Penguin Books, 1949, Call number: DG77.B34 (Box 12)
  - End of the road. [New York: Avon Books, 1960, Call number: PS3552.A75 E5 1960 (Box 12)
  - Sot-weed factor. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1964, Call number: PS3552.A75 S6 1964 (Box 12)
  - Come back, Dr. Caligari. Garden City, N.Y.: Anchor Books, 1965, Call number: PS3552.A76 C6 1965 (Box 12)
  - Where's Annie? [New York: Dell Pub. Co.], 1964, Call number: PS3552.A824 W47 1964x (Box 31)
  - Mirror of art: critical studies translated and edited with notes and illustrations by Jonathan Mayne. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1956, Call number: N6847.B362 1956 (Box 12)
  - Flowers of evil (Les fleurs du mal) with translations by Geoffrey Wagner and an introduction by Enid Starkie. Norfolk, Conn.: New Directions, 1946, Call number: PQ2191.F6 1946 (Box 58)
    Additions, January 1983
  - Juice. New York: Dell, 1965, Call number: PS3552.E26 J753 (Box 32)
  - Article 92: murder-rape. Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett, 1964, Call number: PS3552.E3198 A78 1964 (Box 27)
  - Room for a body. New York: Ballantine Books, 1964, Call number: PR6003.A525 F5 1964 (Box 27)
  - Catch a falling spy. New York: Macfadden-Bartell, 1964, Call number: PS3503.E48 C3 1964 (Box 44)
  - De l'amour: psychologie de la vie affective et sexuelle. Paris: Le Cercle du Livre, 1952, Call number: HQ21.B445 1952 (Box 15)
  - Joyce-again's wake: an analysis of Finnegan's Wake. Seattle: University of Washington Press, 1965, Call number: PR6019.J85fZbe (Box 5)
  - Ben-Yehuda's pocket English-Hebrew Hebrew-English dictionary David Weinstein, associate editor. New York: Washington Square, 1961, Call number: PJ4822.B4 1961 (Box 57)
  - Tell me another morning: a novel. New York: Harper, 1961, Call number: PS3552.E71915 T4 1961 (Box 66)
  - Matter and memory authorized translation by Nancy Margaret Paul and W. Scott Palmer [pseud.]. New York: Doubleday., 1959, Call number: B2430.B4 M313 1959 (Box 1)
  - Two sources of morality and religion translated by R. Ashley Audra and Cloudesley Brereton, with the assistance of W. Horsfall Carter. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1935, Call number: B2430.B4 D42 1935a (Box 13)
  - Trial at Bannock. New York: Avon Books, a division of the Hearst Corporation, 1963, Call number: PS3552.I357 T7x 1963 (Box 27)
  - Still circling Moose Jaw. New York: Bantam, 1966, Call number: PS3503.B547st (Box 1)
  - Blake: selected poetry with an introduction and notes by Ruthven Todd. New York: Dell, 1960, Call number: PR4142.T6x (Box 13)
  - William Blake: a selection of poems and letters edited with an introduction by J. Bronowski. [Harmondsworth, Middlesex; Baltimore]: Penguin Books, 1958, Call number: PR4142.B7 (Box 13)
  - Archetypal patterns in poetry: psychological studies of imagination. New York: Vintage Books, 1958, Call number: PN1031.B63 1958 (Box 13)
  - Joyce's benefictions. Berkeley: University of California Press, 1964, Call number: PR6019.J85 B65 (Box 18)
  - History of aesthetic. Cleveland, OH: Meridian Books, 1957, Call number: BH81.B65h 1957 (Box 12)
  - Sandro Botticelli (1444/5-1510) text by Frederick Hartt. New York: H. N. Abrams in association with Pocket Books, 1953, Call number: ND623.B7 H32 (Box 23)
  - Ireland Translated by John Fisher. [London: Vista Books; New York: Viking, 1960, Call number: DA978.B613 1960 (Box 13)
  - Death likes it hot. New York: New American Library, 1960, Call number: PS3543.I26 D44 1955 (Box 27)
  - No good from a corpse with an introduction by Anthony Boucher. New York: Collier Books, 1964, Call number: PS3503.R154 N6 1964 (Box 27)
  - Of Plymouth Plantation selected and edited with an introduction by Harvey Wish. New York: Capricorn Books, 1962, Call number: F68.B8086 1962 (Box 15)
  - Soldier's story. New York: Popular Library, 1964, Call number: D756.B7 1964 (Box 31)
  - Twentieth-century German verse. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1963, Call number: T1174.B76t 1963 (Box 1)
  - Stendhal; a collection of critical essays. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1962, Call number: PQ2441.B78s (Box 12)
  - Fragments of life, metaphysics, and art. New York: B. Wheelwright Co., 1953, Call number: N66.B75 (Box 2)
  - Wuthering Heights with a foreword by Geoffrey Moore. New York: New American Library, 1959, Call number: PR4172.W7 1959 (Box 12)
  - Bold saboteurs. New York: Lancer Books, 1962, Call number: PS3552.R67 B6 1962 (Box 13)
  - All the paintings of Pieter Bruegel edited by Valentin Denis; translated from the Italian by Paul Colacicchi. New York: Hawthorn Books, 1961, Call number: ND673.B73 D42 (Box 20)
  - History of eroticism. New York: L. Stuart, 1963, Call number: HQ458.B838h 1963 v.2; Title page missing. (Box 6)
  - Unicorn. New York: William Sloane Associates, 1960, Call number: PS3552.U3327 U9x (Box 69)
  - Let my people go: the story of the Underground Railroad and the growth of the abolition movement. Boston: Beacon Press., 1959, Call number: E450.B89 1959 (Box 36)
  - Pilgrim's progress With an afterword by F.R. Leavis. New York: New American Library, 1964, Call number: PR3330.A1 1964b (Box 30)
  - Re Joyce. New York: W. W. Norton, 1965, Call number: PR6019.J85 W69 1965 (Box 6)
  - Right to an answer. New York: Ballantine Books, 1966, Call number: PR6052.U638 R5 1966 (Box 30)
  - Brain pickers. New York, N.Y.: Dell, 1963, Call number: PS3552.U73215 B73 1963 (Box 32)
  - Naked lunch. New York: Grove Press, 1959, Call number: PS3552.B945na (Box 66)
  - San Franciscans. New York: Dell Pub. Co., 1963, Call number: PS3503.U746 S33 1963 (Box 27)
  - Love affair translated by Joseph Green. New York, N.Y.: Dell, 1965, Call number: PQ4807.U83 A813 1965 (Box 26)
  - Lamp for nightfall. New York, N.Y.: Macfadden-Bartell, 1965, Call number: PS3505.A322L3 1965 (Box 13)
  - Skeleton key to Finnegans wake. New York: Viking Press, 1961, Call number: PR6019.J85fZc 1961 (Box 2)
  - Caligula and Cross purpose = Le malentendu translated by Stuart Gilbert. [England]: New Directions, 1947, Call number: PQ2605.A38 M34 1947 (Box 58)
  - Fall translated from the French by Justin O'Brien. New York: Knopf, 1957, Call number: PQ2605.A3734 C4813 1957 (Box 58)
  - Handful of silver. New York: Berkley Pub., 1964, Call number: PR6005.A486 H3 1964 (Box 31)
  - Invasion - they're coming! New York: Bantam, 1964, Call number: D761.C333 1964x (Box 31)
  - Fortune in dimes. New York: Pocket Books, 1964, Call number: PS3553.A7825 F67 1964 (Box 31)
  - Essay on man: an introduction to a philosophy of human culture. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1944, Call number: B3216.C33 E8 1944b (Box 31)
  - Papal encyclicals in their historical context [edited by]by Anne Fremantle; with an introduction by Gustave Weigel. New York: New American Library, 1956, Call number: BX860.A36 1956 (Box 38)
  - Guignol's band translated from the French by Bernard Frechtman and Jack T. Nile. New York: New Directions, 1954, Call number: PQ2607.D47 G9E (Box 69)
  - D'un chateau l'autre: roman. Paris: Gallimard, 1961, Call number: PQ2607.E834 D2 1961 (Box 67)
  - Little to the east. New York: Popular Library, 1963, Call number: PS3553.E48 L58 1963 (Box 31)
  - Don Quixote of La Mancha translated and with an introduction by Walter Starkie. New York: New American Library, 1964, Call number: PQ6329.A25 S7 1964 (Box 1)
  - Deceitful marriage: and other exemplary novels a new translation with a foreword by Walter Starkie. [New York]: New American Library, 1963, Call number: PQ6329.C213 1963 (Box 13)
  - Paul Cèzanne text by Meyer Schapiro. New York: N. H. Abrams, 1952, Call number: ND553.C3 S29 1952 (Box 35)
  - High window. New York: Pocket Books, 1965, Call number: PS3505.H3224 H5 1965 (Box 12)
  - Long goodbye. New York: Pocket Books, Inc., 1955, Call number: PS3505.H3224 L6 1955 (Box 26)
  - My father, Charlie Chaplin. New York: Popular Library, 1960, Call number: PN2287.C3 C36 1960 (Box 31)
  - Canterbury tales = Tales of Caunterbury edited by A. Kent Hieatt and Constance Hieatt; selected, with translations, a critical introduction, and notes by the editors. New York: Bantam Books, 1964, Call number: PR1867.H53 1964 (Box 1)
  - Enormous radio and other stories. New York: Berkley Publishing Corp., 1958, Call number: PS3503.H6428 E5 1958 (Box 25)
  - Brigadier and the golf widow. New York: Bantam Books, 1965, Call number: PS3505.H6428 B7 1965 (Box 31)
  - Wapshot chronicle with decorations by Alex Tsao. New York: Bantam Books, 1958, Call number: PS3505.H6428 W3 1958 (Box 41)
  - Ward six, and other stories a new translation by Ann Dunnigan; with an afterword by Rufus W. Mathewson. [New York]: New American Library, 1965, Call number: PG3456.A15 1965 (Box 20)
  - Stories of Anton Tchekov edited, with an introduction, by Robert N. Linscott. New York: The Modern Library, 1932, Call number: PG3456.A13 L56 1932 (Box 58)
  - Pictorial history of Western art. [New York]: New American Library, 1964, Call number: N5302.C45 1964 (Box 44)
  - Murder is announced. New York: Pocket Books, 1951, Call number: PR6005.H66 M847 1951 (Box 32)
  - Mirror crack'd. New York: Pocket Books, 1964, Call number: PR6005.H66 M5 1964 (Box 67)
  - N or M? New York: Dell Pub. Co., 1964, Call number: PR6005.H66 N20 1964x (Box 67)
  - Second World War, v.5: Closing the ring. New York: Bantam Books, 1962, Call number: D743.C47 1962 v.5 (Box 26)
  - Shakespeare of London. New York: Dutton, 1957, Call number: PR2907.C5 1957 (Box 12)
  - Precis de decomposition. [Paris]: Gallimard, 1949, Call number: PQ2605.J46 P7 1949 (Box 44)
  - Until the real thing comes along. New York: Bantam Books, 1964, Call number: PS3553.L28 U5 1964 (Box 31)
  - U. S. Navy in action, a heroic account of the greatest naval fighting force the world has ever known. Derby, Conn.: Monarch Books, 1963, Call number: E182.C55 (Box 24)
  - Barbarossa: the Russian-German conflict, 1941-1945. New York: New American Library, 1966, Call number: D764.C55 1966 (Box 1)
  - Open square. Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett Publications, 1962, Call number: PS3553.L283 O63 1962 (Box 26)
  - Landscape into art [by] Kenneth Clark. Boston: Beacon Press, 1961, Call number: ND1340.C541 1961 (Box 15)
  - Nude: a study in ideal form. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday Anchor Books, 1959, Call number: N73.C54n 1959 (Box 15)
  - Death of a painted lady. New York: Avon Books, a division of the Hearst Corporation, 1962, Call number: PR6053.L43 D42 (Box 25)
  - Thomas l'imposteur: histoire. [Paris]: Gallimard, 1964, Call number: PQ2605.C64 T3 1964 (Box 15)
  - Infernal machine, and other plays. New York, N. Y.: New Directions, 1963, Call number: PQ2605.C64 M3E 1963 (Box 29)
  - Fire in his eye. New York: New American Library, 1963, Call number: PS3505.O2 F57 1963 (Box 25)
  - Seventeenth-century painting. New York: Viking Press, 1964, Call number: ND180.C6 (Box 25)
  - Reason and nature: an essay on the meaning of scientific method. New York: Harcourt, Brace and company, 1931, Call number: B945.C53 R4 1931 (Box 59)
  - Poems and prose selected with an introduction by Kathleen Raine. Harmondsworth; Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1957, Call number: PR4472.R3 (Box 13)
  - Coleridge: selected with an introduction and notes by G. Robert Stange. [New York: Dell Pub. Co.], 1959, Call number: PR4478.A35 S8 (Box 15)
  - Claudine married translated by Antonia White. New York: Berkley Publishing Corporation, 1965, Call number: PQ2605.C67 C5E 1965 (Box 12)
  - Gigi, and selected writings With a foreword by Elaine Marks. [New York]: New American Library, 1963, Call number: PQ2605.O28 G53 1963 (Box 15)
  - Six novels by Colette: Claudine at school, Music-hall sidelights, Mitsou, Cheri, The last of Cheri, Gigi. New York: The Modern Library, 1960, Call number: PQ2605.O28 A24 1960 (Box 28)
  - Four voyages to the new world: letters and selected documents translated and edited by R.H. Major; introduction by John E. Fagg; consulting editor Henry Bamford Parks. New York: Corinth Books, 1961, Call number: E114.M24 1961 (Box 40)
  - Darwin and the naked lady: discursive essays on biology and art. New York: G. Brazilier, 1962, Call number: PR6005.O388 D3 1962 (Box 29)
  - Family and a fortune: and More women than men: two novels. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1965, Call number: PR6005.O3895 F35 1965 (Box 12)
  - Joyce's Portrait, criticisms & critiques. New York: Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1962, Call number: PR6019.J85pZc (Box 13)
  - Adolphe and the red notebook With an introduction by Harold Nicolson. [New York]: New American Library, 1959, Call number: PQ2211.C24 A7 1959 (Box 25)
  - By love possessed. Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett, 1961, Call number: PS3505.C839b 1961 (Box 26)
  - Treasury of art masterpieces: from the Renaissance to the present day. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1958, Call number: ND1170.C7 1958 (Box 39)
  - Lady of quality, dialogues translated from the French of Crebillon le fils. [North Hollywood, Calif.: Brandon House], 1964, Call number: PQ1971.C6 T11E (Box 7)
  - Aesthetic as science of expression and general linguistic. New York: Noonday Press, 1964, Call number: BH204.C7 1964 (Box 44)
  - Is 5. New York: Boni & Liveright, 1926, Call number: PS3505.C91i 1926; Contains various notations in the hand of Schwartz attempting to figure the rhyme scheme and a 14-line poem on the last page. (Box 10)
    Ex libris: Delmore Schwartz. June 9, 1929, [and] au libraire du M. Maurice Zolotow, dams l'ann?e January 1933.
  - Twelve dancing princesses: and other fairy tales. [New York]: New American Library, 1964, Call number: PZ8.D138 T94 1964 (Box 15)
  - Frazer acquittal: a mystery by Stephen Ransome [pseud.]. New York: Popular Library, 1955, Call number: PS3507.A728 F72 (Box 19)
  - Ring around Rosy. Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett Publications, 1964, Call number: PS3515.U5425 R56 1964 (Box 31)
  - Like a river of lions. New York: Paperback Library, 1963, Call number: PS3554.E413 L54 1963 (Box 19)